Arne Oldberg Collection
Music Division, Library of Congress
- Correspondence, circa 1892-1962, undated (Box 86-90)
  - Oldberg Family Correspondence, circa 1894-circa 1911, undated
    Arranged alphabetically and chronologically therein.
    - Oldberg, Emma, circa 1894 (Box-folder 86/1)
    - Oldberg, Emma, 1895 and undated (Box-folder 86/2)
    - Oldberg, Karl [son] (Box-folder 86/3)
    - Oldberg, Minnie [Mary Georgianna, née Sloan, 1876-1968] (Box-folder 86/4)
    - Oldberg, Olga [Arne's sister], circa 1894 (Box-folder 86/5)
    - Oldberg, Olga, 1895 and after (Box-folder 86/6)
    - Oldberg, Oscar, circa 1893 (Box-folder 86/7)
    - Oldberg, Oscar, Aug.-Sept. 1893 (Box-folder 86/8)
    - Oldberg, Oscar, Oct.-Dec. 1893 (Box-folder 86/9)
    - Oldberg, Oscar, Jan.-Feb. 1894 (Box-folder 86/10)
    - Oldberg, Oscar, Mar.-Apr. 1894 (Box-folder 86/11)
    - Oldberg, Oscar, May-June 1894 (Box-folder 86/12)
    - Oldberg, Oscar, Oct.-Dec. 1894 (Box-folder 86/13)
    - Oldberg, Oscar, Jan.-Feb. 1895 (Box-folder 86/14)
    - Oldberg, Oscar, Mar.-May 1895 (Box-folder 86/15)
    - Oldberg, Oscar, Sept.-Oct. 1898 (Box-folder 86/16)
    - Oldberg, Oscar, Nov.-Dec. 1898 (Box-folder 86/17)
    - Oldberg, Oscar, Jan.-Feb. 1899 (Box-folder 86/18)
    - Oldberg, Oscar, Mar.-Apr. 1899 (Box-folder 86/19)
    - Oldberg, Oscar, May 1899 (Box-folder 86/20)
    - Oldberg, Oscar, 1900-1909 (Box-folder 86/21)
    - Oldberg, Oscar, 1910 (Box-folder 86/22)
    - Oldberg, Oscar, 1911 and after (Box-folder 86/23)
    - Oldberg, Oscar, miscellaneous (Box-folder 86/24)
    - Oldberg, Rudolf [Arne's uncle] (Box-folder 86/25)
    - Oldberg, Ruth [née Terry, first wife of Arne Oldberg's brother Virgil] (Box-folder 86/26)
    - Oldberg, Virgil [brother of Arne] (Box-folder 86/27)
    - Oldbergs, unidentified (Box-folder 86/28)
    - Oldberg, European relatives (Box-folder 86/29)
    - Parritt, E. [Emily Parritt, née Hogue, 1820-1908], Arne Oldberg's grandmother (Box-folder 86/30)
  - Letters by Arne Oldberg to his family, circa 1892-circa 1900, undated
    Arranged chronologically.
    - before 1892 (Box-folder 87/1)
    - Aug. 1893 (Box-folder 87/2)
    - Sept. 1893 (Box-folder 87/3)
    - Oct. 1893 (Box-folder 87/4)
    - Nov. 1893 (Box-folder 87/5)
    - Dec. 1893 (Box-folder 87/6)
    - Jan. 1894 (Box-folder 87/7)
    - Feb. 1894 (Box-folder 87/8)
    - Mar. 1894 (Box-folder 87/9)
    - Apr. 1894 (Box-folder 87/10)
    - May-June 1894 (Box-folder 87/11)
    - Oct.-Nov. 1894 (Box-folder 87/12)
    - Dec. 1894 (Box-folder 87/13)
    - Jan.-Feb. 1895 (Box-folder 87/14)
    - Mar.-June 1895 (Box-folder 87/15)
    - Aug.-Sept. 1898 (Box-folder 87/16)
    - Oct.-Nov. 1898 (Box-folder 87/17)
    - Dec. 1899 (Box-folder 87/18)
    - Jan.-Feb. 1899 (Box-folder 87/19)
    - Mar.-Apr. 1899 (Box-folder 87/20)
    - May-June 1899 (Box-folder 87/21)
    - Wedding announcement, 1900 (Box-folder 87/22)
    - 1900 and after (Box-folder 87/23)
    - Undated (Box-folder 87/24)
  - Letters to the Oldbergs
    Arranged alphabetically by correspondant.
    - Ahlberg, Karl (Box-folder 88/1)
    - Altschuler, Modest (Box-folder 88/2)
    - American Academy of Arts and Letters (Box-folder 88/3)
    - American Music Society (Box-folder 88/4)
    - "A" miscellaneous (Box-folder 88/5)
    - Beach, John (Box-folder 88/6)
    - Beecher, Carl (Box-folder 88/7)
    - Bernstein, Leonard [material on] (Box-folder 88/8)
    - Blauel, Fred (Box-folder 88/9)
    - Bliss, James A. (Box-folder 88/10)
    - Bloomfield-Zeisler, Fannie (Box-folder 88/11)
    - Bloomington Normal Symphony Society (Box-folder 88/12)
    - Borowski, Felix (Box-folder 88/13)
    - Breitkopf & Härtel (Box-folder 88/14)
    - Buhlig, Richard (Box-folder 88/15)
    - "B" miscellaneous (Box-folder 88/16)
    - C. C. Birchard and Company (Box-folder 88/17)
    - Cadman, Charles Wakefield (Box-folder 88/18)
    - Cameron, Bessie (Box-folder 88/19)
    - Cartwright, Ada (Box-folder 88/20)
    - Chadwick, George Whitefield (Box-folder 88/21)
    - Chicago Symphony Orchestra (Box-folder 88/22)
    - Cincinnati Symphony Orchestra (Box-folder 88/23)
    - Clayton F. Summy Company (Chicago, Ill.) (Box-folder 88/24)
    - Cleveland Orchestra (Box-folder 88/25)
    - Cliff Dwellers (Club) (Box-folder 88/26)
    - Cole, Rossetter G. (Box-folder 88/27)
    - Crew, Henry and Helen (Box-folder 88/28)
    - "C" miscellaneous (Box-folder 88/29)
    - Damrosch, Frank (Box-folder 88/30)
    - Damrosch, Walter (Box-folder 88/31)
    - Day, Harry Brooks (Box-folder 88/32)
    - Defauw, Désiré (Box-folder 88/33)
    - De Lamarter, Eric (Box-folder 88/34)
    - DeShazu, Susie (Box-folder 88/35)
    - Dickinson, Clarence (Box-folder 88/36)
    - "D-E" miscellaneous (Box-folder 88/37)
    - Farwell, Arthur, 1905 (Box-folder 88/38)
    - Farwell, Arthur, 1906 (Box-folder 88/39)
    - Farwell, Arthur, 1907-1909 (Box-folder 88/40)
    - Farwell, Arthur, 1910 (Box-folder 88/41)
    - Farwell, Arthur, 1911-1915 (Box-folder 88/42)
    - Farwell, Arthur, undated (Box-folder 88/43)
    - Farwell, George L. (Box-folder 88/44)
    - Fischer, William Arms (Box-folder 88/45)
    - Flammer, Harold see also G. Schirmer, Inc. (Box-folder 88/46)
    - Fleisher Music Collection see Philadelphia Free Library, Edwin A. Fleisher Music Collection
    - Foote, Arthur (Box-folder 88/47)
    - "F" miscellaneous (Box-folder 88/48)
    - G. Schirmer, Inc. see also Sonneck, Oscar; Flammer, Harold (Box-folder 88/49)
    - Gale, Robert Griggs (Box-folder 88/50)
    - Gabrilowitsch, Ossip (Box-folder 88/51)
    - Garland, Hamlin (Box-folder 88/52)
    - Gleason, Frederic Grant (Box-folder 88/53)
    - Gottschalk, L. G. (Box-folder 88/54)
    - "G" miscellaneous (Box-folder 88/55)
    - Heyman, Katherine Ruth (Box-folder 88/56)
    - Hopwod, Grace B. (Box-folder 88/57)
    - Hughes, Rupert (Box-folder 88/58)
    - Hyllested, August and Clara (Box-folder 88/59)
    - "H" miscellaneous (Box-folder 88/60)
    - Ivy, A. C. (Box-folder 88/61)
    - "I-J" miscellaneous (Box-folder 88/62)
    - Keeton, W. Elmer (Box-folder 88/63)
    - Kelley, Edgar Stillman (Box-folder 88/64)
    - Knight, F. M. (Box-folder 88/65)
    - Koelling, Adolph (Box-folder 88/66)
    - Kreider, Noble (Box-folder 88/67)
    - Kroeger, Ernest R. (Box-folder 88/68)
    - Krone, Max T. (Box-folder 88/69)
    - Krueger, Karl (Box-folder 88/70)
    - Kunwald, D. E. (Box-folder 88/71)
    - "K" miscellaneous (Box-folder 88/72)
    - Lambrier, Télémaque (Box-folder 88/73)
    - Leschetizky, Theodor and Mrs. (Box-folder 88/74)
    - Library of Congress. Copyright Office (Box-folder 88/75)
    - Liebling, Emil (Box-folder 88/76)
    - Löbel, Jacques (Box-folder 88/77)
    - Longy, Georges (Box-folder 88/78)
    - Lundström, Emil F. (Box-folder 88/79)
    - Lutkin, P. C. (Box-folder 89/1)
    - "L" miscellaneous (Box-folder 89/2)
    - MacDowell Club of Memphis (Box-folder 89/6)
    - Malko, Nicolai (Box-folder 89/4)
    - Mason, Daniel Gregory (Box-folder 89/5)
    - McCormick, Cyrus (Box-folder 89/3)
    - Middelschulte, Wilhelm (Box-folder 89/7)
    - Minneapolis Symphony Orchestra (Box-folder 89/8)
    - Minnesota Music Teacher's Association (Box-folder 89/9)
    - Mount St. Mary's College (Los Angeles, Calif.) (Box-folder 89/10)
    - Mulfinger, George (Box-folder 89/11)
    - Musical Courier (Box-folder 89/12)
    - Musician's Club of New York (Box-folder 89/13)
    - "M" miscellaneous (Box-folder 89/14)
    - National Federation of Music Clubs (Box-folder 89/15)
    - National Institute of Arts and Letters (Box-folder 89/16)
    - National Society of Arts and Letters (Box-folder 89/17)
    - National Society of Music (Box-folder 89/18)
    - New York Philharmonic Society (Box-folder 89/19)
    - Northland, Louis G. (Box-folder 89/20)
    - Northwestern University (Evanston, Ill.) (Box-folder 89/21)
    - "N" miscellaneous (Box-folder 89/22)
    - Oberhoffer, Emil (Box-folder 89/23)
    - Oberndorfer, Marx E. (Box-folder 89/24)
    - Oglesby, George D. (Box-folder 89/25)
    - Ohioana Library Association (Box-folder 89/26)
    - Oliver Ditson Company (Box-folder 89/27)
    - Pacak, Oswald (Box-folder 89/28)
    - Parker, Horatio (Box-folder 89/29)
    - Philadelphia Free Library, Edwin A. Fleisher Music Collection (Box-folder 89/30)
    - Pottag, Max (Box-folder 89/31)
    - Prentner, Marie (Box-folder 89/32)
    - "P" miscellaneous (Box-folder 89/33)
    - Reichhold Music Award Committee (Box-folder 89/34)
    - Reiner, Fritz (Box-folder 89/35)
    - Rodzinski, Artur (Box-folder 89/36)
    - "R" miscellaneous (Box-folder 89/37)
    - Schaum, John W. (Box-folder 89/38)
    - Schick, George (Box-folder 89/39)
    - Seaman, Maurice S. (Box-folder 89/40)
    - Sée, Marc (Box-folder 89/41)
    - Seligman, Alfred Lincoln (Box-folder 89/42)
    - Shepherd, Arthur (Box-folder 89/43)
    - Solomon, Izler (Box-folder 89/44)
    - Sonneck, Oscar see also G. Schirmer, Inc. (Box-folder 89/45)
    - Stebbins, Charles A. (Box-folder 89/46)
    - Stewart-North, Isabel (Box-folder 89/47)
    - Stiedry, Fritz (Box-folder 89/48)
    - Stock, Frederick A. (Box-folder 89/49)
    - Stokowski, Leopold (Box-folder 89/50)
    - Sudler, Louis (Box-folder 89/51)
    - Szell, George (Box-folder 89/52)
    - "S" miscellaneous (Box-folder 89/53)
    - Thomas, Theodore (Box-folder 89/54)
    - Tindall, Glenn M. (Box-folder 89/55)
    - Troendle, Theodora (Box-folder 89/56)
    - Twachtman, Emma (Box-folder 89/57)
    - "T" miscellaneous (Box-folder 89/58)
    - University of Chicago (Box-folder 89/59)
    - University of Illinois (Box-folder 89/60)
    - University of Southern California (Box-folder 89/61)
    - Voelcker, C. (Box-folder 89/62)
    - Volpe, Arnold (Box-folder 89/63)
    - Walker, Susan B. (Box-folder 89/64)
    - Wessel, Mark (Box-folder 89/65)
    - Weidig, Adolf (Box-folder 89/66)
    - White, Robert (Box-folder 89/67)
    - Wigent, John (Box-folder 89/68)
    - Woollett, Ernest (Box-folder 89/69)
    - Young, Malcolm (Box-folder 89/70)
    - Ysaÿe, Eugène (Box-folder 89/71)
    - "W-Z" miscellaneous (Box-folder 89/72)
    - Miscellaneous (Box-folder 89/73)
  - Letters of Condolence to Mrs. Oldberg, 1961-1962
    - A (Box-folder 90/1)
    - B (Box-folder 90/2)
    - C (Box-folder 90/3)
    - D (Box-folder 90/4)
    - E (Box-folder 90/5)
    - F (Box-folder 90/6)
    - G (Box-folder 90/7)
    - H (Box-folder 90/8)
    - J (Box-folder 90/9)
    - K (Box-folder 90/10)
    - L (Box-folder 90/11)
    - M (Box-folder 90/12)
    - N (Box-folder 90/13)
    - O (Box-folder 90/14)
    - P (Box-folder 90/15)
    - R (Box-folder 90/16)
    - S (Box-folder 90/17)
    - T (Box-folder 90/18)
    - V (Box-folder 90/19)
    - W (Box-folder 90/20)
    - X-Z (Box-folder 90/21)
    - Miscellaneous (Box-folder 90/22)
- Biographical Materials (Box 81, 90)
  Biographical sketches, articles, and writings.
  - Arne Oldberg, Biographical Sketch and Composition Listing (Box-folder 90/23)
  - Miscellaneous, 1959 and undated (Box-folder 90/24)
  - The Musical Courier, vol. XXXIII, no. 6, August 5, 1896 (Box 81)
- Writings (Box 90)
  - Articles, "The American Composer" (Box-folder 90/25)
  - Miscellaneous (Box-folder 90/26)
- Photographs (Box 90)
  - Two photographs, one is unidentified and undated; the other is of Mrs. Baker, Arne Oldberg's first teacher, 1890 (Box-folder 90/27)
- Programs, 1891-1961 (Box 78-79, 90)
  Programs, repertoire listings, commencement programs, and bulletins.
  Arranged by organization and chronologically therein.
  - Theodore Thomas Orchestra/Chicago Symphony Orchestra
    - 1911-1918 (Box-folder 78/5)
  - Chicago Symphony Orchestra
    - 1919-1939 (Box-folder 78/6)
    - 1941-1947 (Box-folder 78/7)
    - 1949-1958 (Box-folder 79/1)
  - Chicago Symphony Orchestra, repertoire listing
    - 1891-1958 (Box-folder 79/2)
  - American University Concerts, Chicago Symphony Orchestra, March 8, 1953 (Box-folder 79/3)
  - North Shore Music Festival
    - 1909 and 1915 (Box-folder 79/4)
    - 1919 and 1927 (Box-folder 79/5)
    - 1929 (Box-folder 79/6)
  - Miscellaneous orchestras (Box-folder 79/7)
  - Northwestern University commencement programs
    - 1936 and 1961 (Box-folder 79/8)
  - Northwestern University School of Music Bulletin
    - 1905-1940 (Box-folder 79/9)
    - 1940-1941 (Box-folder 79/10)
  - Miscellaneous programs, including repertoire listings, circa 1903-1950 (Box-folder 90/28)
- Financial Materials (Box 90)
  - Miscellaneous financial documents, circa 1890 (Box-folder 90/29)
- Clippings (Box 90)
  - Miscellaneous clippings (Box-folder 90/30)
- Awards and Certificates (Box 80)
  - National Institute of Arts and Letters book, 1961 (Box-folder 80/1)
  - National Institute of Arts and Letters constitution and list of members, 1915 (Box-folder 80/1)
  - Ohioana award, 1959 (Box-folder 80/2)
  - Cliff Dwellers membership card (Box-folder 80/3)
- Miscellany, circa 1887-circa 1950, undated (Box 80, 90)
  - Handwritten book with Oldberg's student piano repertoire, undated (Box-folder 80/4)
  - Student autograph book, circa 1887 (Box-folder 80/5)
  - Address book (Box-folder 80/6)
  - Copy of letter from Jacobsohn concerning World's Fair, 1893 (Box-folder 80/7)
  - Miscellaneous writings about Oldberg, 1950, undated (Box-folder 80/8)
  - Calling card dies (Box-folder 80/9)
  - Guide to Antwerp, 1894 (Box-folder 80/10)
  - "A Practical Universal Money." Typescript by Oscar Oldberg, undated (Box-folder 80/11)
  - Miscellaneous items, including maps, postcard and memorial book for Oscar Oldberg (Box-folder 90/31)
Appendix A: Index of Musical Compositions by Arne Oldberg
Note: This index only includes those works which are found in the collection.
13 Trois morceaux for piano, op. 13
15 Quartet, 2 violins, viola, and cello, op. 15, C minor
16 Quintet, 2 violins, viola, cello, and piano, no. 1, op. 16, B minor
17 Concerto for piano and orchestra, no. 1, op. 17, G minor
18 Serenade pastorale, oboe, clarinet, horn, bassoon, and piano, op. 18
19 Twelve variations for orchestra, op. 19
22 Four outdoor songs for contralto and orchestra, op. 22
23 Symphony, no. 1, op. 23, F minor version
23 Symphony, no. 1, op. 23, E minor version
24 Concertino for piano and chamber orchestra, op. 24
24 Quintet, 2 violins, viola, cello, piano, op. 24, C# minor
28 Sonata, piano, op. 28
29 Festival overture, op. 29
34 Symphony, no. 2, op. 34, C minor
35 Symphonic variations, organ and orchestra, op. 35
36 June rhapsody, op. 36
38 At Night, Fantasy for orchestra, op. 38
40 Symphonic variations, two pianos and orchestra, op. 40
41 Symphony, no. 3, op. 41, F minor
43 Concerto for piano and orchestra, no. 2, op. 43
45 Sonata, cello and piano, op. 45
45b Sonata, viola and piano, op. 45b
46 Concerto (all' antico) for violin or cello and orchestra, op. 46
47 The Sea, Fantasy for orchestra, op. 47
48 Sinfonia, op. 48
48 Sonata, violin and piano, op. 48
48a Sonata, cello and piano, op. 48a
49 Six variations for orchestra, op. 49
50 Symphony, no. 4, op. 50, B minor
51 Sonata, violin and piano, op. 51
52 Concerto for piano and orchestra, no. 3, op. 52
53 Ballade (for orchestra), op. 53
53 Trois chansons Françaises, op. 53
54 Symphony, no. 5, op. 54, E minor
Works without opus numbers, in alphabetical order:
Legend, for orchestra
Pandora, cantata for soprano, tenor, baritone, mixed chorus and orchestra
Paolo and Francesca, dramatic overture for orchestra, op. 21
Quartet, 2 violins, viola, and cello, a
Quartet, 2 violins, viola, and cello, b
Quartet, 2 violins, viola, and cello, no. 2, D major
Quintet, 2 violins, viola, cello, and piano, no. 2, B minor
Rhapsody, no. 2
Sextet, string quartet, horn, and piano, B minor
Sinfonia, G minor
Sinfonietta, no. 6, G major
Le son du cor for horn and orchestra
Sonatina, string orchestra, C major
St. Francis of Assisi
A study in relativity
Symphony, no. 7, C minor
Symphony in D major, Festival
Trio, E minor, piano, violin, cello
Trio, violin, viola, and cello
Valsette for two pianos
Miscellaneous songs, Aveu and Keramos